Alexa Parks 🗸

User Experience and Voice User Interface Designer

Hi there

I'm a trained graphic designer with an affinity towards VUI design. VUI design is the most exciting modality, and lends itself to deep thought, attention to detail, and looking around every corner.

I've lived in Seattle for 10 years (with a 2 year sabbatical in Tokyo, Japan) and I'm an outdoor enthusiast. My favorite hike this year was Fragrance Lake, and I'm looking forward to hiking Oyster Dome.

Email

alexaparks22@gmail.com

Phone

(206) 512-0323

Sample PDF of selected work available upon request.

Education

Seattle Central Creative Academy

A.A.S. Graphic Design Seattle, WA 2017-2019

University of California, Irvine

B.A. Psychology and Social Behavior

Irvine, CA 2012-2014

Orange Coast College

A.A. General Education Costa Mesa, CA 2010-2012

Tools

Voice design Voice Flow Interaction design Sketch, Figma Adobe suite Illustrator, inDesign **Development** Sublime, Git, GitHub Miscellaneous Asana, Microsoft Office

Career History

Voice User Interface Designer

Amazon's Alexa Audio 2019-2022

Lead VUI designer

I lead several projects from research and ideation to launch.

Voice Move launched 2021

Move music, podcasts, and radio to and from your Echo devices and groups.

Media Resume launched 2021

A new setting on Echo devices and the Alexa app that moves audio seamlessly from your home Echo devices to Echo Auto.

Kindle Assistive Reader launched 2022 Updated accessibly feature that enables Alexa to read your audiobooks on your Echo devices and in the Alexa app.

Alexa Audio Mobile App: Design Lead Mobile and interaction design and ownership for coordination and sign-off.

Alexa Audio Growth Team: Design Lead Responsibilities included design and management of voice hints and push notifications regarding feature awareness.

Front-End Developer

Palisades Holding Company 2016-2017 Developed and designed responsive email templates, quality assurance dashboards, and web pages.

Skillset

Voice user interface design

- Voice flows
- Sample dialogs
- Text-to-speech prompts
- Voice hints
- Prompt audits
- User research
- AB testing

Multimodal design

- · Multimodal flows and mocks
- Mobile interface flows and mocks
- Push notification copy and mocks
- · Web design

